I'm kind of cheap. I hate paying for
simple apps that I feel like should have
been a free Chrome extension or
something. So lately, I've been using AI
to whip up my own custom tools. Nothing
super fancy. No billion dollar startup
ideas.
Sweet Baby Rays barbecue sauce.
Nothing I intend to like actually sell.
Just quick scrappy apps that solve
little problems for me. And honestly,
it's way easier than you'd think. So
today, I'm going to show you how you can
use AI to stop overpaying for
underwhelming software. Let's get into
it. The first app I want to create is
well, not something that you normally
have to pay for actually, but I don't
have access to it on my Mac, and that's
Microsoft Paint. Sometimes you want to
just like edit an image real quick, like
circle something or sketch something on
it real quick, and on a Mac, you don't
have that super simple software like
Microsoft Paint. So, let's go ahead and
build it. For this first one, I'm
actually going to test warp.dev.
It's an agentic development environment.
And if we check out their pricing, they
do actually have a free plan where you
can try it out. So up to 150 AI requests
per month. You can use Claude Opus 4.1
and GPT5 and pretty much all the best
models. So I think I can do it on the
free plan. So I went ahead and
downloaded Warp here. And this is what
it looks like. Down at the bottom, they
have like a terminal mode, an agent
mode, and an auto detection mode. So,
let's just leave it on auto. And then
for the models, we have all sorts of
models available. Again, this is the
free plan. My favorite model for coding
was actually 03 Pro, which looks like we
don't have access to that here, but
Claude 4.1 Opus is also really, really
good. I've had really great success
coding with this one. So, let's leave it
on Claude 4.1 Opus. And let's see if I
could just give it a prompt to build the
thing. Here's my prompt. Make a
Microsoft Paint clone. I should be able
to draw, use a paint bucket, create
arrows, type, and have all the color
options. I'd also like to be able to
drag an image directly into the app and
edit the image, and then save a new
version of the image that's been edited.
I'm hoping I can just give it a prompt
like this, and it will know what to go
off and do. So, let's see what happens.
All right, I'll create a Microsoft Paint
clone with all the features, etc., etc.
And then it created a task list. This is
how you know it's kind of an agentic
workflow is when it creates a task list
and then starts working through all of
the tasks. That's usually a pretty good
sign that it's going to work out well.
But let's find out what we end up with
off of just a single prompt inside of
warp. Okay, so it looks like once it
goes through each step, I do have to
apply changes. I wonder if there's like
the equivalent of a yolo mode here, but
let's go ahead and apply changes. and it
has moved on to the next step. Now, down
in the very bottom right corner, there
is a button that if I hover over it, it
says auto approve all agent actions for
this task. I'm going to go ahead and
turn that on and let it just run through
all of the steps. Okay, so it ran for a
couple minutes here and it opened up
this app inside of my browser. Let's go
ahead and give it a test. We've got our
pencil tool here. Can I draw? Yes, I can
draw. Let's go ahead and close off our
loop. Let's use our bucket tool. Can I
paint bucket fill? Okay, so I don't
think the paint bucket tool is working.
Nothing seems to be happening when I
click anywhere. Don't know what this
button Oh, that's the arrow button.
Okay, so I can create arrows. That part
works. Can I add text? This is text I
made. Yeah, that worked. Let's see. What
is this? Is a broom. Okay, so the broom
is the erase. I've got like a line tool
where I can just draw different lines.
Our square tool, our circle tool, can
change brush size. Yeah, I mean
everything's kind of working except for
our paint bucket tool.
We don't make mistakes. We have happy
accidents.
Paint bucket tool did not seem to work
for whatever reason. Let's see. Does the
save image button work? Yeah, it saved
it as painting.png. Can I upload an
image? Let's open up this thumbnail
here. Yeah, I mean it opened up the
thumbnail and I could draw on my
thumbnail here. So everything's working
except for the paint bucket. Let's jump
back to warp real quick and just say
everything's working perfectly except
for the paint bucket. When using the
paint bucket, it should fill in the
space with a solid color. It took just a
few seconds here. So let's refresh our
page and see if our paint bucket is
working. So I'll select the paint
bucket. Let's go yellow. And yeah, it
seems to be working. Let's try green.
Let's uh let's draw a rectangle. I'll
draw a blue rectangle here. And then
we'll put orange inside the rectangle.
Yeah. I mean, it does what Microsoft
Paint does, and I did it with a couple
prompts. Pretty freaking cool. And I
drew you a self-portrait. You know how
people send voice notes because it's
faster than typing? The only downside is
that they just sit there as audio.
That's why I use Whisper Flow. It gives
me the same speed advantage, but
everything I say turns into clean
formatted text in whatever app I'm
using. Chat, GPT, Notion, Cursor, you
name it. It even edits out the ums and
fixes little corrections like Tuesday,
wait no, Wednesday, and formats lists,
emails, or code automatically. The
biggest benefit is when I'm prompting AI
tools, if I type something short and
rushed, I get a basic response. But when
I speak, it's even easier to give more
context and get way better results. And
if you're coding in tools like cursor,
warp, or claude, flow actually
understands your code. It handles
technical terms, tags, files, and even
gets variable names right. They also
recently added snippets, little voice
shortcuts that expand into full text. I
can use them for things like my calendar
link or a terminal command I use often.
I just say it and Flow drops in the
whole thing instantly. If you want to
give it a shot, you can get an extra
month of Flow Pro on top of the 14-day
free trial with the code Mr. Eflow. So,
while other people are leaving context
out because typing takes too long,
you'll be shipping better results by
just speaking with Flow. Thank you so
much to Whisper Flow for sponsoring this
video. Now, let's get back to it.
Another tool that I think would be very,
very helpful to have is a tool that
converts any image file into a specific
image file. So, for example, I can drop
in a WEBP file and it'll convert it to a
JPEG. Or I can drop in an AVIF file and
convert it to a JPEG. As somebody who
edits a lot of videos and does a lot of
website building, having some of these
other file types like WEBP and AVIF and
TIFF files and things like that can get
really annoying and I like to just
convert them all to JPEG files before
using them in a video or a place like
that. Now, there are free tools out
there like this free convert that I
found and it will convert one file at a
time, but if you want to bulk drop in
like 20 images and have it work through
each image, well, you got to pay for
that feature. And their lowest plan is
$13 a month for a tool where you drop in
images and it changes the image file. We
can do better than that. We could build
our own that's free to use whenever we
want to use it and works just as well.
For this one, we'll use Claude. And I'll
just use the Claude interface directly
over at Claude AAI. And then I'll also
use my little whisper tool to explain
what I'm looking for. So I'll click into
the prompt box here. I want an app where
I can drag and drop any image file type
and it will convert that file type into
a JPEG. So whether it's a webp, an AVIF
file, a TIFF file, any of those types of
files, I want to be able to drop it in
to this app and convert it into a JPEG.
Now, also, I want to be able to bulk
drag and drop a ton of files in at once
and have it work through one by one and
convert each file to a JPEG so I can
bulk upload a bunch of files. I want it
to be built on Python so I can run it on
my desktop without even needing an
internet connection. Whisper just
converted everything I just said into a
giant wall of text. I'm just going to
double check it real quick to make sure
it got all my ideas correctly.
Everything looks good. So, let's go
ahead and submit it and let Claude build
this out for us. Claude gets to work
writing the code for us. It split the
chat off to the left and we can actually
see the code being written in real time
off to the right. So one prompt and
we've got our code written over here.
Features universal format support. So
WEBP, AVIF, TIFF, PNG, BMP, GIF or GIF,
HEIC, and more. Bulk processing, convert
multiple files at once, etc. So it looks
like it designed it to do everything I
want it to do. And here it's telling me
how to install it. So I need to install
a few dependencies on my computer first.
I have a folder on my computer called
code where I put the little apps that
I'm building. I'll just create a new
folder here and we'll call it image
convert. Now I'm going to open up my
terminal. And this should work the same
way whether you're on a Mac or a PC.
We'll change our directory to make sure
we're in the right place. So now I'm in
this image convert directory that I just
created. Follow the instructions that it
told us to do. So we'll install pillow.
I guess since I'm on a Mac, I actually
have to use pip 3 install pillow instead
of just pip. That's what claude just
told me at least. And then our next
step, we copy this code that it told us
to install tinter dnd2. I don't know if
that's how you pronounce it or not.
Paste this in. Now it's installed that.
And it wants me to save this file that
it created for us as image converter.
py. I'm going to come to this folder, go
into this image convert that we just
created. We'll create a new document
inside this folder and we need to name
it image_converter.py.
Copy our code from over here. Paste it
into our text editor here. And we will
save it. And it saved it as an RTF file
and not a Python file. So I'm going to
remove the RTF and we'll use py. Now if
I grab the code that it tells me to use
to run this file here. Pop this back
into our terminal. And look at this
image.j JPEG converter. It's all built
and we can just drag and drop files in
here to convert them to JPEG. So, I have
this PNG image on my computer. Let's go
ahead and drag this image in and see if
it'll convert this PNG to a JPEG. The
colors are a little wonky. I'd probably
want to fix that. But, let's find out if
the software actually works. So, I'll
convert to JPEG. It asked me where I
want to save it. I'll put it in my
downloads folder here. Conversion
complete. One successful. And looking in
my downloads folder, we can see that it
created the image and saved it as a
JPEG. Here I have this file on my
computer. That's a WEBP file. Let's go
ahead and toss this one in. All right,
one file ready for conversion. Convert
to JPEG. I'll just save it to downloads
again. And successful. And there we go.
It saved that exact same image as a JPEG
instead of a WEBP file. One last test. I
want to throw multiple images in there
and see if it will batch convert
multiple. So I'll pick a few PNGs. I've
got this one here. Toss it in. Here's
another one that I have a PNG. I'll toss
this one in. Let's throw in a WEBP file
as well. I've got this is a WEBP file.
So, I'll toss that in. So, now we have
three files ready for conversion. Let's
convert to JPEG. Save them all to our
downloads folder. Conversion complete.
Three successful. Let me double check.
And look at this. Man with kitten JPEG.
MW Beard inverted JPEG. And this image
as a JPEG. So, it does exactly what I
want it to do. Don't have to pay
monthly. And I can drop a batch of files
in here. Pretty cool. Finally, I want to
build an app that can transcribe videos
for me. So, if I'm recording a video for
my YouTube channel and I want the
transcription before it's live on
YouTube, so I can, you know, write notes
about it or get my chapter titles or
things like that, I can do that. Now,
there's tools out there that will do
transcriptions for you, like Descript,
which charges as little as 16 bucks a
month. And there's also tools like Rev
that can do transcriptions that give you
45 minutes free per month, but then you
need to upgrade for 10 bucks a month if
you want to keep transcribing. So, let's
build a tool real quick where I could
drag and drop any video in and it will
transcribe it for me. Now, the tool I'm
going to make won't technically be free
to use. I'm going to need to use an API
key from a service that does the
transcription. But when I use my API
key, it's going to allow me to
transcribe video and audio files, but
it's going to cost like fractions of a
penny per minute to do it. My favorite
transcription API is actually from
Assembly AI. They do speech to text, but
if we look at their pricing, when you
first sign up, you get $50 in free
credits, which gets you up to 185 hours
of transcription. And then you move to
like a pay as you go plan. And then it
costs 27 per hour. So you could record a
full hourong video and it will only cost
you a little more than a quarter to
transcribe the whole thing. So we'll go
ahead and use the API from Assembly AI.
I've already created an account, so I'll
go ahead and log in. You can see when I
log into my Assembly AI account, I've
only used about $862
of my credits and still have over $41
remaining. So, here's how we're going to
build this app. We're going to use our
API key from Assembly. So, I'm going to
go over to API keys here on the left,
and I'm going to create a new API key,
and we're going to call this demo video
because I'm going to delete this API key
after this video is live because you
never want to share your API keys with
anybody, otherwise other people will be
able to use your account. So, let's go
ahead and create this and then we'll
copy the API key that it created for us
for this demo video. Now, to create the
app this time, I'm just going to go
ahead and use chatgpt to create it. And
just for some bonus points, I'm on a
free ChatgPT plan. You can see down in
the bottom left, I'm logged into my free
account. So, we're going to see if we
can build this app without using one of
the premium accounts. So, inside of our
prompt box, I'm going to go ahead and
use Whisper Flow again here. build me an
app where I can drag and drop either a
video or audio file into the app and it
will transcribe all of the audio from
whatever I upload. We're going to use
the Assembly AI API key for the actual
transcription service. And I want this
to be browserbased. So I want to be able
to drag and drop a file straight into
the browser, have it transcribe it, and
then in the same window give me back the
transcription. So, I basically just
explained it using Whisper, but it's
going to need the API key that we just
created from Assembly AI to build this.
So, let's go ahead and put here is my
API key for Assembly AI. And I'll paste
it in like that. Use this for the
transcription service. Because I haven't
used my think longer for the day, let's
go ahead and turn on think longer and
get it to work a little bit harder on
this one. It thought for 29 seconds and
now it's writing my code for me. I tried
running it. It gave me this error right
here. So, I'm going to just feed this
error right back into chatgpt. I
received the following error when trying
to run this inside of the canvas in
chatgpt. So, I just gave it some
instructions and now I'm going to go
ahead and put the error I got in quotes
so it can see it. And uh let's see if it
can fix this for us. I ran into a couple
more bugs. I had to tell chat GPT the
bugs and asked it to fix the bugs a
couple times, but now I think we've got
a version that's working. And again,
still on the free plan here. So, if I
click on preview, we can see it loads up
our app here. I don't like the
background color and text choice it used
like, you know, black on a dark gray
background. Not ideal. Obviously, an
easy fix. Just tell it to change the
font color. But let's go ahead and drop
in an audio video file here. In fact,
this is the video of the ad read that I
did earlier in the video you're watching
for Whisper Flow. If I drag and drop
this in, we can see it uploads my file.
You can barely read it, but you can see
status uploading Whisper Flow and the
percentage going up. Now, we have status
transcribing. This may take a minute.
And we have our transcript from the ad.
You know how people send voice notes
because it's faster than typing. The
only downside is that they just sit
there as audio. So, it pulled in the
whole video I just recorded and
transcribed it. And if I jump back over
to Assembly AI over here, click on my
cost here, you can see that it cost me
slightly more than three pennies. Tools
like Descript and Rev are great, but if
I can transcribe something for 3 cents
versus 10 bucks a month, might be a
little bit preferable. So, there you
have it. There's a few tools that I
found paid versions for and went, let's
just go ahead and create this ourselves
so we don't have to pay a monthly fee
for it. And this is one of the things
that I love using AI for lately. It's
not going to like recreate an entire
like HubSpot CRM for you right now. But
little apps that you might find helpful
or finding little bottlenecks in your
business where you can build a mini app
to solve that bottleneck, AI is amazing
for that. And I just gave you three
demos with three different tools. We
used Warp, we used Claude, we used
ChatGpt. All of them were able to build
these little basic apps that solve small
problems for us. AI is great at that.
And hopefully this got your wheels
turning about other little apps that
maybe you might want to create for
yourself. Something that you're sick of
paying, you know, $9.99 a month for
because it can be built really quickly
and then used for free in perpetuity
after that. and I can't wait to see what
you create. All of the apps that I've
created are actually available on my
GitHub. So, if you want to download them
for free and build off them and iterate
off them, they are available on GitHub.
I will link up my GitHub in the
description below if you want to go
check them out and download them.
They'll be totally available for free,
open source, you can do what you want
with them. If you do build something
cool, tag me on X or Instagram or
Facebook or whatever your platform of
choice is. Let me know what you built. I
want to see it. Maybe I'll even do a
future video where we round up some of
the cool tools that you guys have built
based on trying some of this stuff. But
that's what I got for you today. Thank
you so much for tuning in. I really,
really appreciate you hanging out,
nerding out with me. Some of this stuff
is so much fun. I just have an absolute
blast playing with these AI tools and
building stuff and putting things into
the world that didn't really exist
before I worked with AI to make them
exist. So, super fun stuff. I'm so happy
and appreciative that I have people that
want to nerd out and watch this stuff
with me. And uh yeah, if you want more
stuff like this, let me know in the
comments and I will do my best to
accommodate. And again, if you like
this, like, subscribe, do all the things
that all the other YouTubers tell you to
do. It really helps the channel grow.
Really appreciate you. I'm done
rambling. Hopefully, I'll see you in the
next one. Bye-bye. Thank you so much for
nerding out with me today. If you like
videos like this, make sure to give it a
thumbs up and subscribe to this channel.
I'll make sure more videos like this
show up in your YouTube feed. And if you
haven't already, check out
futuretools.io where I share all the
coolest AI tools and all the latest AI
news. And there's an awesome free
newsletter. Thanks again. Really
appreciate you. See you in the next one.